字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
In the 11th century, the invasion of the Danish army and the Vikings
公元11世纪 丹麦军队和维京人的入侵
only continued to intensify.
愈演愈烈
1012 A.D. ENGLAND
（公元1012年 英格兰）
Then in October,
那年十月
after years of continuous assaults,
在持续多年的不断攻击后
a turning point was reached.
战争的转折点出现了
ESTATE OF KING SWEYN NEAR JELLING, DENMARK
（斯韦恩国王庄园 丹麦 耶灵附近）
Then you wish to withdraw our soldiers from England?
那么 您是希望我们从英格兰撤军？
Not withdraw. Let them rest.
不是撤退 是让他们休息一下
Marching in winter will deplete our military strength.
冬天里行军 那只会耗尽我们的军力
And our soldiers abroad need to recuperate.
我们派过去的士兵也是需要休整的
Yes, as you wish.
好的 遵命
The summer.
夏天
We will launch a major attack next summer.
明年夏天我们会发动大进攻
I, too, shall lead an army into battle.
我自己也会带领军队参战
So we have a break all of a sudden?
所以我们是忽然就能休息了？
I want to go home.
我想回家
There's no need for the pirates either.
我们也不需要那些海盗了
I thought we could earn a lot this year.
我还以为我们今年能赚很多钱呢
The regimented soldiers aren't moving either.
那些兵团士兵也都没动
This is what it means to work for hire.
这就是看天吃饭的难处
What will Askeladd do?
阿谢拉特打算怎么办？
Askeladd.
阿谢拉特
If this keeps up, winter's gonna be awfully hard.
我们冬天要是就这么过的话 岂不是很寂寞？
And we've ransacked all the good villages.
那些富裕村庄已经都被我们搜刮完了
That's true.
没错
What do you plan to do?
你打算怎么做呢？
We'll do as we must.
没办法
We'll migrate like the birds.
我们就像迁徙的鸟
We'll go where the food is.
吃的在哪里 我们就去哪里
NEAR THE LOIRE RIVER, KINGDOM OF FRANCE
（法兰西王国 卢瓦尔河附近）
Move it!
别偷懒！
They've got a ram!
他们有攻城锤！
Gather the crossbows!
十字弓手们集合！
One, two…
一 二…
Shoot in two groups!
两组弓箭手交替发射！
Ready!
准备！
Shoot!
发射！
It's no use! Retreat!
没用的！撤退！
Looks like the Franks are having a skirmish?
这还只是法兰克人之间的小冲突吗？
There are few men in the fortress, while the offense has 800.
堡垒里只有几个人 但进攻的有八百个人
I can't believe they're sieging through the front.
他们想要从前方打进去 简直难以置信
So this is a clan base?
这是一个部落基地咯？
What do you think?
你怎么看？
Doesn't it smell of treasure?
这里都能闻到财宝的味道了 不是吗？
So that's your aim?
所以这就是你的目标吗？
Shall we do it, Askeladd?
阿谢拉特 我们要不要干？
We'll side with the attackers.
我们站到进攻方那一边
We'll break open their treasury and take what's inside.
到时候打开金库 拿走里面的东西
All right!
好！
I was wondering what we were doing in the middle of nowhere.
我说呢 我们在这种乡下地方干嘛
Askeladd comes through!
阿谢拉特 好主意！
Our leader's judgment is never wrong!
我们首领的判断从来都不会出错！
We'll regain what we lost in England!
我们会把在英格兰损失的钱赚回来！
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
You're up.
该你上了
Time to fight.
该去参加战斗了
EPISODE 7: PARTNER IN WAR
（第七集：北方人）
Contact the attacking side's leader.
你去联络上进攻方的首领
Tell him this:
告诉他：
"You're terrible in battle. Watching you is unbearable.
“你们打仗打得很糟糕
Thus, our contingent is here to help.
因此 我们的军队是来帮忙的
We're a once-in-a-lifetime godsend.
我们是千载难逢的天赐好帮手
We will surely guide you to victory.
我们一定能引领你们走向胜利
If the fortress falls, we will take half the spoils.
如果堡垒被攻破 那么我们就拿走一半战利品
We can join the attack tomorrow morning."
我们明天早上会再进攻一次”
After delivering the message, stick around to see the reaction.
告诉他这段话之后 你要待在他们的营房 观察情况
Then leave.
听明白的话 就去吧
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Go, Thorfinn.
走啊 托尔芬
How many do you think I've killed so far?
你觉得我到现在为止杀了多少人了？
I've been your scout and support from the rear.
我给你们当探子 在后方支持你们
I've accomplished enough.
我已经成就了足够多战功
Yet…
但是 你…
What?
什么？
You want a reward?
你想要奖励？
Once you've reached an agreement, I'll give you three gold coins.
等你跟对方达成协议 我会给你三块金币
I swear to the God Tyr.
我向战神发誓
Don't mess with me.
别糊弄我
You're scary!
你可真吓人啊！
I was only teasing.
我开玩笑而已
However…
不过
in that case, you'll have to bring me at least one helmeted head.
这么说的话 你至少得 给我带回来一颗军队首领的人头
He never changes.
他真是一点没变
Is it wise to task him with important negotiations?
但是 把这么重要的谈判交给他 真的可以吗？
Inferior soldiers can get nervous.
下等兵们容易被激怒
They're often killed before negotiations even begin.
所以他们常常在谈判之前就被杀掉了
Who'd bother with a stray like him?
谁又在乎他这么一个流浪汉呢？
What do you want, kid?
小子 你要干嘛？
This is no place for a child!
这里不是小孩子该来的地方！
I'm an envoy.
我是被派来的特使
Does anyone here speak Norse?
这里有人会说挪威语吗？
What's with this kid?
这孩子怎么回事？
What language is that?
这是什么语言？
He's not a Frank.
他不是法兰克人
A spy from the fortress?
难道是堡垒派过来的间谍？
We'll just take him.
我们还是抓了他吧
I am an envoy.
我是个特使
Is there anyone who speaks Norse?
这里有人能说挪威语吗？
Give you half the spoils?
给你们一半战利品？
These mercenaries are pushing their luck!
这些雇佣兵胆子也太大了！
"Give you half the spoils…"
“给你们一半的战利品…”
You're very confident, aren't you?
你很自信啊 是吧？
You Norman brat.
你这个诺曼人小混蛋
Norman?
诺曼人？
The northerners who attacked England?
那些进攻英格兰的北方人？
"The northerners who attacked…"
“那些进攻英格兰的北方人？”
Your strategy is obvious.
连个小孩子都能明白
If you just attack the front gate, your men will only die.
如果你只进攻前门 那么你的人就只会不断被杀掉
Defense around the lake is light.
湖边的防守很弱
That's where we would target.
那才是我们会攻击的目标
That's ill-advised.
这么想很欠考虑
The rivers flowing into the lake are treacherous
那里的河流越往上越湍急
not to mention the waterfalls.
况且还有瀑布
Our ships were wiped out going downstream.
我们的船在往下游走的时候 都被干掉了
That's what it means to attack from the lake.
这就是从湖上攻击的结果
"That's what it means to attack…"
“这就是从湖上攻击的结果”
Do you
你这是拒绝我们的提议吗？
In that case, Askeladd's 100 men will side with the fortress.
这样的话 阿谢拉特这一百人的军队 就会加入堡垒那一边的军队
"…side with the fortress."
“…堡垒那一边的军队”
My death won't change that.
现在杀掉我的话 也一样
If I don't signal the end of our negotiations,
如果我不发出我们谈判结束的信号
you will make an enemy of 100 of the north's fiercest fighters.
一百个最勇猛的北方战士 就会变成你们的敌人
Fine.
好吧
Your Excellency!
阁下！
However,
但是
if we learn your words are false, we will chop your head!
如果我们发现你说的不是真的 我们就会砍下你的头！
If you are sincere,
如果你们是真诚的
in the name of Jesus Christ, we will equally share our bread.
那么以耶稣基督的名义 我们会公平分享战果
"…we will equally share our bread."
“…我们会公平分享战果”
Return my dagger to me.
把我的匕首还给我
It is a memento of my father.
那是我父亲的遗物
That's Thorfinn's signal.
那是托尔芬的信号
One high arrow, two low.
一箭高 两箭低
Let's hurry.
我们得快点
We'll pass over the ridge before the moon rises.
月亮升起来前 我们就得穿过山脊
We've been guarding the ship this whole time.
这段时间我们只是守船
I want to fight too.
我也想战斗
Damn that fat general.
该死的胖将军
Over there.
那里有东西
Dragon!
是龙！
On the mountain!
在山上！
A dragon…
一条龙…
A dragon climbed the mountain?
一条龙在爬山？
Yes.
对
A report said all the ship's guards saw it last night.
报告说 昨晚所有守船的卫兵都看到了
It's an omen, Your Excellency.
阁下 这是个征兆啊
I'd like to see one someday.
我也想看看龙
Brat.
小子
Are your comrades coming?
你的同伴们什么时候来？
"I'd like to see…"
“我也想看看龙…”
The sun is already high.
时间已经不早了
"The sun is already high."
“时间已经不早了”
Just start the assault, fatty.
胖子 你只管发动攻击吧
You'll soon see.
很快你就会明白的
You just insulted me now, didn't you?
你刚骂了我 对吧？
It seems tonight's entertainment will be your beheading.
看来今晚的娱乐活动就是砍下你的头
Advance!
行进！
Charge!
冲锋！
Oh, no. It's already started.
哦 不好 战斗已经开始了
We're late, you bastards!
混蛋们 我们晚了！
Give it all you've got!
大家全力以赴！
The battlefield is waiting!
战场在等着我们呢！
It's the same as last time!
这一次和之前一样！
Damn it.
该死的
Put a ladder up on the west side!
西边放一把梯子！
Sacrifice as many as needed!
别管牺牲多少人！
Hey. Which one is the opposition leader?
嘿 哪一个是对面的首领？
You see the one with feathers in his helmet?
哦 看到那个头盔上有羽毛的人吗？
That's him.
就是他
"A helmeted head."
一个首领的人头
Hey, you!
嘿 你！
You lied to me, didn't you?
你骗了我 是吧？
Kill him!
杀了他！
Kill the brat!
杀了那小子！
You bastard!
你个混蛋！
He escaped, and the fortress won't fall!
他逃走了 堡垒也攻不破！
What's wrong with this army?
这支军队是怎么回事？
You think I'll let you go home if it snows?
你们以为下雪了我就会让你们回家？
But I won't!
我不会的！
Not until you take that fortress!
攻破堡垒之前是不会让你们回家的！
Huh?
啊？
Heave-ho!
起锚！
Row!
用力划！
Full speed ahead!
全速前进！
-Aye!
-好！
First to arrive gets twice the payment!
第一个到的拿两份奖金！
Put everything into it!
用尽全力！
I see!
我看到了！
They're on our side!
他们是我们这边的！
Everyone advance! Take the fortress!
所有人向前冲！攻破堡垒！
They carried their ship over the ridge.
他们居然把他们的船搬过了山脊…
Don't waver!
不要放弃！
The 80 men on the right, go to the harbor!
你们右边这八十个人 去港口！
Crossbows, come with me!
十字弓手 跟我来！
You're ill-prepared!
你们没准备好！
The lake is not only a poor bulwark, but it's also a perfect entry point.
这片湖可不只是一个破防御 它还正好能让我们划进来
All right! Head straight in!
好了！直接进去！
What? They're piercing through our shields at this range?
什么？离得这么远 他们也能射穿我们的盾牌？
-They got Olov! -We're in trouble!
-他们杀掉了奥洛夫！ -我们有麻烦了！
Askeladd!
阿谢拉特！
Crossbows, huh?
十字弓是吧？
Those will cause some fair damage.
它们确实会造成一定的破坏
Now's our chance.
现在是我们的机会
Maximum hits before they land!
在他们靠岸前 尽可能射杀他们！
A child?
一个孩子？
What?
什么？
The assault stopped?
攻击停下来了？
Maybe they ran out of arrows.
可能他们的箭已经射光了
Prepare to land, you bastards!
混蛋们 准备靠岸！
This is our chance!
这是我们的机会！
Oh, no!
哦 不！
-Kill the bastard! -Damn kid!
-杀了他！ -该死的孩子！
Don't let him get away!
别让他跑了！
Go!
上！
Storm the fortress!
扫荡整个堡垒！
All right, tear this place apart!
好了 把这地方统统拆掉！
Are they sure they can hold the front gate?
他们确定自己能守住大门吗？
Men, take care of these guys quickly.
赶紧的 把这些人解决掉
Heave-ho!
起锚！
These Normans are incredible.
那些诺曼人真是不可思议…
My strategy easily wore this fortress down.
我的策略很容易就把这个堡垒攻下了
The fortress captain was killed in battle.
堡垒的队长已经在战斗中被打死了
According to the enemy soldiers, it was the work of a child.
据敌兵说 是个孩子干的
That brat?
那个小子？
These Normans are serious.
可不能小瞧这些诺曼人啊
If we let them go now, they'll become our enemy.
如果我们现在让他们走 他们就会变成我们的敌人
What shall we do?
那我们要怎么做？
They came over the ridge, so they'll carry their ships back again.
他的同伴们是从山上过来的 对吧？
That's when we'll strike.
我们就在那个时候攻击
They're like sitting ducks with their ships on land.
船在岸上的时候 他们就是活靶子
Your Excellency!
阁下！
Report for  Jabbathe!
报告贾巴特将军！
What is it? Speak.
怎么了？说话
The treasury…
金库…
Huh?
啊？
Where is my treasure?
我的财宝哪儿去了？
The houses and church have been raided too.
大户人家和教堂也都被搜刮光了
They took everything of value.
所有值钱的…所有东西都没了
I see…
我知道了…
I wish to congratulate the leader of the Franks!
我想要祝贺一下法兰克人的首领！
We've divided the spoils in two.
我们已经把战利品一分为二了
Your half is the victory.
你那一半是战斗的胜利
Our half is the treasure.
我们这一半就是这些财宝
No complaints, right?
你没意见吧？
I think this is fairly modest
我觉得这么分很公平
since we're letting you keep the fortress!
毕竟我们可是把堡垒让给了你们！
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
-They're going down the waterfall. -Barbarians!
-哦 不！他们要从瀑布下去了 -这群野蛮人！
Ready the ships!
给我备船！
But all the ships in the fortress have been destroyed.
可是堡垒里所有船都被毁掉了
Crooks!
骗子！
Sorry, but I don't understand Frankish.
抱歉 不过我听不懂法兰克话
Now then, shall we set sail?
好了 我们准备好起航了吗？
Thorfinn isn't here yet.
托尔芬还没到
Oh, you're right.
哦 没错
Well then, he must be dead.
那他肯定是死了
I guess we'll take his share, too.
那么 他的那一份也归我们了
He's alive!
他还活着！
What a tenacious kid. Are you injured?
真是个顽强的孩子啊 你受伤了吗？
Askeladd!
阿谢拉特！
The general's head.
这是他们将军的人头
So… you got it.
哇 你真的做到了啊？
You promised.
你保证过的
You cannot refuse me.
你不能拒绝我
I, Thorfinn, warrior of Iceland, son of Thors,
我 托尔芬 冰岛的战士 托尔兹之子
by the sword of my father, challenge you, Askeladd, to a duel
以我父亲的剑之名 向你 阿谢拉特 发起决斗挑战
to avenge my father.
为我父亲报仇
What? He's doing it now?
什么？他现在来这个？
He's tough.
他真是厉害…
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf,
我 阿谢拉特 奥拉夫之子
in the name of my ancestor Artorius,
以我的祖先阿托利斯之名
accept your challenge.
接受你的挑战
However…
但是…
let's do this later!
我们以后再战！
We've got to escape now!
现在我们先要逃命！
Row, you bastards!
混蛋们 划船啊！
Hey!
嘿！
Don't linger, or else they'll seize us on the river!
别磨蹭 不然他们会在河上抓住我们的！
Bastard! Stop taunting me!
混蛋！别再糊弄我了！
Who cares about a dragon?
谁在乎什么龙？
-I'm not scared! -That's right!
-我可不害怕！ -没错！
There it is!
它出现了！
This is farewell!
这就是告别了！
Farewell, Franks!
再见了 法兰克人们！
We're rich!
我们发财了！
We can get through the winter!
我们能熬过这个冬天了！
All right!
好！